

# Dhanasekaran G

Delivering Cost Competitive Optimized solutions with 3+ years of experience in Engineering Design, Project Management, Team handling, Estimation Engineering, Preparing Technical Documentation. Strong Skills in Process development by understanding the Bottle neck operations. Supporting business operations through analysis of key performance indicators and trends A Professional in Design Engineering and Technical sales support, seeking an opportunity to implement my innovative skills and

dhana1035@gmail.com

knowledge for organizational development.

+918870079602

• Ambattur, Chennai

### **PERSONAL INFO**

Date of Birth: 07-12-1996

■Languages Known: English, Tamil

LinkedIn Profile:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dhanaseka ran-g-831a2214a/

### **EDUCATION**

B. Tech - Mechanical Engineering (2014-2018) KARPAGAM INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Coimbatore, Tamilnadu

#### **SOFTWARE**

AutoCAD, Creo, CATIA, NX-CAD, Solid Works, MS Office, PDM, SAP

#### **DEVELOPMENT ACTIVITIES**

- Creation of car area calculator with Local panel Consideration
- An innovative idea on Fixture Modification design was suggested & implemented to NPD department
- Enacted water overflow controller in surface treatment plant at heat treatment Department
- Design and fabrication of selfoperated material handling device

### **PERSONAL COMPETENCIES**

- Organizational learning
- Drive and Commitment
- Time Management and Multi-tasking
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- Strong Knowledge of Design, **Documentation Procedures**
- Good Analytical and Presentation Skills
- Project Management
- Failure Mode & Effect Analysis (FMEA)
- Quality Tools 5Why
- Lateral Thinking

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ITC Infotech India Ltd. deputed at KONE ELEVATORS INDIA PVT LTD, Chennai JULY 2019 - TILL DATE | Design Engineer

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Coordinating with Supply Chain Teams, Project engineers, Front line and Sales Team in understanding / Fulfilling Customer requirement
- Creating independent Cost Optimized Design solutions considering Design for Manufacturability (DFM), Assembly (DFA) to produce optimal Design and Manufacturing based on Engineering Instructions
- Providing Tender & Order bound Engineering drawings with for Installation, Builder, Authority Approval and Customer Approvals for Customized **Elevator Orders**
- Identifying Special Engineering requirements and giving necessary Inputs for other Component Engineering teams
- Involved in quotation support for Tender / Project Engineers for Bidding / Pre-Bidding
- Preparing Models based on Customer requirement adhering to EN Codes & Lift Directives
- Preparing Data list of Components based on Calculation
- Creating Reference Libraries for reducing Engineering Time & to sustain
- 5S Co-Ordinator for Layout Engineering Team

# **FUNCTIONAL EXPERTISE & ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Responding quickly to quality Feedbacks from Sites/ Manufacturing units, Analyzing Root cause for Feedback & take necessary corrective action to avoid similar Quality Issues in future
- Skilled in activity management with intercompany resources and outside vendors in support of manufacturing, assembly, and feedback handling
- Awarded as Best performer for providing good quality Layouts and high number of Job completions in both SOF & Major Projects in Layout
- Leaded several Complex & Prestigious Projects in Tendering
- Handled several Challenging & Prestigious Projects with Maximum Team size of up to 8 Members

## **DELPHI TVS TECHNOLOGIES LIMITED, Chennai**

### JULY 2018 - JUNE 2019 | Draftsman/Quality control trainee

#### **ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Draft and prepare layout drawings for the given structures and components
- Provide drawing according to the given specifications of the component
- Exhaustively reviewing and checking drawings for errors, before being sent to architects, subcontractors, project
- Hands-on experience in blackening, Phosphating, Parcorising and Scheduled Machine Audit
- Performing Distortion studies before and after heat treatment, Analyze FTQ (First-time quality) data
- Interact with internal customers about product issues and take necessary action to achieve 0% internal Customer complaints
- Responsible for monitoring the machine's performance as per standard operating procedure (SOP)